Guide to the Records of the Archaeological Institute of America - New York Society MC.406
New York University Archives
Records of the Archaeological Institute of America - New York Society
1884-2022
1980-2015
New York University Archives
Archaeological Institute of America. New York Society
Kotsonas, Antonis
MC.406
3 Linear Feet in 6 manuscript boxes
348.1 Megabytes in 1 VOB file
The Archaeological Institute of America - New York Society (AIA-NYS) was established in 1884 as a chapter of the Archaeological Institute of America. The Institute and its regional chapters were created to help establish archaeology programs in the United States. Many New York University professors have held leadership positions in the AIA at both the local and national level. The Records of the Archaeological Institute of America - New York Society (dated 1884-2022) consist of materials created and collected by the organization documenting its creation, administrative activities, membership, and public functions. Materials include correspondence, organizational history documents, meeting minutes, newsletters, ephemera from lectures and other events, and financial records. The records reflect the longstanding participation in AIA-NYS leadership and events by NYU faculty and students.
Scope and Contents
The Records of the Archaeological Institute of America - New York Society (dated 1884-2022) consist of materials created and collected by the organization (AIA-NYS) documenting its creation, administrative activities, membership, and public functions. Materials include correspondence, organizational history documents, meeting minutes, newsletters, ephemera from lectures and other events, and financial records. The records reflect the longstanding participation in AIA-NYS leadership and events by NYU faculty and students.
Appraisal
Tax documents, other sensitive documents, and applications for the New York Society Scholars program have been appraised out of the collection. Duplicate ephemera beyond 3 copies were discarded. One optical disc with an image of the Avukana Buddha used in a lecture has been appraised out of the collection and discarded.
Arrangement
Files are arranged alphabetically. Meeting minutes are arranged chronologically.
Conditions Governing Access
Materials are open without restrictions.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Donated by Antonis Kotsonas, President of the New York Society of the Archaeological Institute of America, on behalf of the organization in October 2024; the accession number associated with this gift is 2024.078.
Born-Digital Access Policies and Procedures
Advance notice is required for the use of computer records. Original physical digital media is restricted. An access terminal for born-digital materials in the collection is available by appointment for reading room viewing and listening only. Researchers may view an item's original container and/or carrier, but the physical carriers themselves are not available for use because of preservation concerns.
Historical Note
The Archaeological Institute of America - New York Society (AIA-NYS) was established in 1884 as a chapter of the Archaeological Institute of America. The Institute and its regional chapters were created to help establish archaeology programs in the United States. Many New York University professors have held leadership positions in the AIA at both the local and national level.
Archaeology.; Archaeologists; Archaeology -- Societies, etc.; Kotsonas, Antonis; Archaeological Institute of America. New York Society
- Administrative Records, 1973-1989 (Box 1, Folder 1-3)
- Administrative Records, 1976-1979 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Administrative Records, 1977-1995 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Administrative Records, 1986-1994 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Administrative Records, 1986-1995 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Administrative Records, 1988-2022 (Box 1, Folder 8, Box 2, Folder 1-5)
- Board Member Lists, 1978-2016 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- By-Laws, 2002-2013 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Chron File, 1980-1996 (Box 2, Folder 8-9)
- Committee on Professional Responsibilities, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Correspondence, 1977-2010 (Box 3, Folder 2-3)
- Delegates, 1977-2006 (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Ephemera, undated (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Financial Records, 1978-2014 (Box 3, Folder 6-7)
- Friends, 1994-1996 (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Friends, 1985-2015 (Box 3, Folder 9-10)
- Lecture List, 1951-1968 (Box 3, Folder 11)
- Lectures and Special Events, 1978-2011 (Box 3, Folder 12, Box 4, Folder 1-2)
- Membership -- General, 2013-2016 (Box 4, Folder 3)
- Membership -- Survey, 1991 (Box 4, Folder 4)
- Minutes and Notices Ledger, 1884-1926 (Box 4, Folder 5)
- Minutes and Notices Ledger, 1930-1946 (Box 4, Folder 6)
- Minutes and Notices Ledger, 1947-1966 (Box 5, Folder 1)
- Minutes, 1967-1976 (Box 4, Folder 7-8)
- Minutes and Notices, 1975-1981 (Box 5, Folder 2-3)
- Minutes, 1979-2015 (Box 5, Folder 4-5)
- Newsletter, 1979-2019 (Box 5, Folder 6, Box 6, Folder 1-4)
- Organizational History, 1997, undated (Box 6, Folder 5)
- Photographs, 1994 (Box 6, Folder 6)
- Programming, 1995-1996 (Box 6, Folder 7)
- Prospective Members, 1995 (Box 6, Folder 8)
- Queens Outreach Program, 1992 (Box 6, Folder 9)
- Trustee Handbook, 2009 (Box 6, Folder 10)
- "What is Archaeology?" Promotional Video for Archaeological Institute of America, 2009; UA_MC_406_ER_1